## Jeff Brozena, Teacher, Operator, Analyst

jeff@brozena.net | +1 (570)335-8269 | State College, Pennsylvania

SUMMARY

An operator-teacher with broad and deep experience at one of the country's largest and most respected privately-held Medicaid pediatric dental groups. I was entrusted to set strategic direction, improve core business processes and lead complex change shortly before a cross-generational ownership transfer was expected. My impact at this group was described "like a crater" by its ownership.

**EXPERIENCE** 

The Smilist Management - Manager of Optimization

2018-02-01 — 2018-08-01

**Smiles 4 Keeps Pediatric Dentistry - Practice Operations** 

2012-08-01 — 2017-11-01

 Responsible for a complete digital transformation in the midst of a generational ownership transfer, resulting in accurate third-party valuation of business.

Bedrock Technology - Technician

2012-01-01 — 2012-08-01

Appek Mobile Apps - Project Manager

2011-05-01 — 2012-12-15

Penn State University - Human Computer Interaction Lab - Research Assistant

2009-05-01 — 2010-12-01

Penn State University - Software Trainer

• Promoted to supervisory position in June, 2009.

2007-08-01 — 2009-12-01

AWARDS Rock Ethics Stand Up Award, Penn State University

2011-04-10

**Emerging Scholars Fellowship, Active Minds, Inc.** 

2011-01-01

**EDUCATION** 

## Pennsylvania State University

2008-08-01 — 2019-08-10

BS - Information Sciences & Technology

**SKILLS** 

**Leadership:** Public speaking, Systems thinking, Whole systems management, Written & verbal clarity, Motivational interviewing, Situational leadership

**Digital transformation:** Software training, Transformational change, Change management, Strategic planning, Business analysis

**Healthcare information technology (HIT):** HIPAA compliance, Electronic data interchange (EDI), Electronic medical record (EMR), Analytics, SQL, Product management, Systems integration, Software integration, Electronic remittance advice (ERA), Clinical decision support

**Program management:** Process improvement, Project management, Process optimization, Process management, Lean Six Sigma, Kaizen

## REFERENCES

**Dr Ross Wezmar, DDS:** Jeff worked in an organization experiencing both cross-generational and analog-to-digital transformations. He was presented with the delicate balance of transitioning a 40-year-old male-dominated enterprise to a second-generation female-directed organization in the fast-evolving provider side of healthcare. Throughout the transformation he kept steady focus the ultimate goal of a successful transition. He shepherded cross-generational familial change in a focused and intelligent manner, holding true to both the original entrepreneurial drive and the aspirations of the second generation. All parties came to see the need for change while retaining the drive of the original owner. Much of this success is due to Jeff continually bringing clarity and tenacity of purpose to his position as a change-maker.

**Dr Katherine Wezmar Poepperling, DDS:** Jeff used his tremendous intellect combined with his insight into the human spirit to propel us in such a positive direction. He has given me a gift a peace which I didn't really think was possible.